<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.cinemamode.app</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Cinema Mode</name>
  <developer id="io.github.human9mil">
    <name>human9mil</name>
  </developer>
  <icon type="stock">org.cinemamode.app</icon>
  <summary>One-click cinema mode for movie lovers with multi-monitor desks</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      I've always loved movies — really loved them, the kind where you dim the
      lights and give the screen your full attention. But at my desk, with two
      or three monitors glowing on either side, a movie never quite felt like a
      movie. There was always some other window spilling light into the room,
      pulling my eyes away from the story.
    </p>
    <p>
      Cinema Mode is the fix I built for that. One click before the movie
      starts, and every monitor except the one you're watching on actually
      turns off — no dimming tricks, no black overlay windows, the displays
      themselves go dark. Click again when the credits roll, and everything
      comes back exactly where you left it. It's a small thing, but if you're
      a fellow movie lover working from a multi-monitor desk, I think you'll
      feel the difference the first time you use it.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>One click to blank every monitor except the one you choose</li>
      <li>Instantly restores every display to its exact previous position and resolution</li>
      <li>Remembers your favorite "main" monitor between launches</li>
      <li>A cinema-themed interface that feels like part of the show</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Made with love, for cinema lovers everywhere.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.cinemamode.app.desktop</launchable>
  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Standing by, one click away from cinema mode</caption>
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/human9mil/cinemamode/main/packaging/screenshots/screenshot-standing-by.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Now showing, every other monitor blanked</caption>
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/human9mil/cinemamode/main/packaging/screenshots/screenshot-now-showing.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/human9mil/cinemamode</url>
  <provides>
    <binary>cinemamode</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2026-07-04">
      <description>
        <p>Shows real monitor names (e.g. "LG UltraGear (DP-2)") instead of bare connector names, read straight from each display's EDID. Also fixes a bug where a hung kscreen-doctor call could freeze the app indefinitely, adds diagnostic logging for troubleshooting, and includes several small robustness and packaging improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-07-04">
      <description>
        <p>Adds a global keyboard shortcut (Meta+Shift+C) and a system tray icon, so cinema mode can be toggled without opening the window.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-07-04"/>
  </releases>
</component>
